

Muhammad Zaki Fuadi

Data Analyst | Data Enginner mzfuadi@gmail.com +6285348932285 linkedin.com/in/mzfuadi97/ Banjarmasin, South Kalimantan Experienced in interpreting and analyzing data to drive growth for a customer care department. I am a fast learner and can work with a team or individually. Provide the input, analytics, insight, and business intelligence needed to drive data-driven decisions, Passionate with technology especially in all Data engineering, Data Analyst, and Customer Service Measurement also.

SKILLS QUALIFICATION

Software Skills

- Python, R Programming
- SQL database, Spreadsheet
- Google Cloud Platform
- Tableau, PowerBI, Looker
- Google Big Query, dbt
- Docker, Virtual Machine
- Airflow (Apache Spark)
- ArcGIS, QGIS
- Terraform
- KNIME

Research Skills

- Data Visualization
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Natural Language Processing
- Time Series Analysis
- Multivariate Analysis
- A/B Testing

Soft Skills

- Presentation Skill
- Public Speaking
- Negotiation Skill
- Team Work
- Leadership
- Critical Thinking
- Problem-Solving

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist (Intern) Dibimbing | Bukit Vista - Remote

May 2022 - Present

The company specializes in providing unique and memorable hospitality experiences through its portfolio of properties and services.

- Classify it into cataract and non-cataract classes, extract features using feature engineering techniques, and gain insights to solve problems.
- Perform data checking and cleaning using data cleaning methods, conduct data manipulation if necessary, gain data insights by analyzing relationships between various issues and proposed solutions, and conduct feature extraction for further analysis.
- Grouped data after feature extraction can be utilized for machine learning processing by comparing the accuracy of multiple models to determine the best model for data detection and classification.

Contributor Feb 2022 - Present

Upwork.com - Remote

A freelancing platform connecting businesses with freelancers from various fields to collaborate remotely on projects.

- The task involves designing the formatting and navigation elements in Power BI to enhance the visual appeal and user experience of the reports.
- The task is to create a Power BI Dashboard, which involves designing and developing a visual representation of data using the Power BI tool for effective data analysis and reporting purposes.
- The task entails utilizing data analysis techniques and generating graphical reports as a Data Analyst specializing in graph reporting



Data Engineer - Data Fellowship Program

Nov 2022 - Feb 2023

IYKRA - Jakarta, Indonesian

IYKRA helps corporates and public or individual learners answer their business questions by building better use of data. DataFellowship is one of their programs to create Data Professionals with knowledge, real project execution, and soft skill development.

- Received training such as a webinar, hands-on, and practice cases about Data engineering.
- Solved practical cases per module such as data ingestion with Python and Airflow, Big Data processing tools with Spark Kafka dbt, and visualizing the data using Looker.
- Final Project: Banking Marketing

Project Details: Define customer segmentation on the bank using RFM, design end-to-end data pipeline with Lambda Architecture, so the business intelligence/analyst could choose between whether to use batched data or real-time streamed data and create analytics dashboard based on data from the analytics database (data warehouse) and derive some insight from it.

Data Analyst Oct 2021 - Sep 2022

PT. Trio Motor - Banjarmasin, Kalimantan Selatan

Main Dealer for Honda Motorcycle businesses in South Kalimantan and Central Kalimantan

- Develop big data analysis in each business line (sales, unit entry, parts) and business support (customer care) using SQL, Spreadsheet, and PowerBI (Dax Query).
- Monitoring quality use case implementation of Main Dealer and develop data warehouse by SQL Server.
- Increase the business value in 5 departments (sales, unit entry, parts, marketing, logistics, and customer service center).
- Project-based: Sales Department (Return Order, Buying Cycle, Migration Path, RFM Funneling, Monitoring Achievement Funneling), Technical Service Department (Service Cycle, Near Far Analysis, KPB, and Coverage Area), Part Department (Hotline Order Monitoring), HC3 / CRM department (Leads Management (H1/H2), Complaint Handling Monitoring, Honda People Monitoring, Network Operational Standard Monitoring vs Survey Monitoring), Marketing Department (Product Domestic Regional Brand Analysis).

Supervisor CS Measurement

Oct 2021 - Sep 2022

PT. Trio Motor - Banjarmasin, Kalimantan Selatan

Main Dealer for Honda Motorcycle businesses in South Kalimantan and Central Kalimantan

- Monitoring of customer service satisfaction survey activities conducted by vendors & internal Main Dealer, analyzing the results of ongoing surveys, and reminding the department if there are findings of problems in customer service.
- Ensuring Corrective Action (remedial, monitoring, preventive) Department runs on every dealer who still has deficiencies in customer service
- Increase customer care KPI for the company from 85.70% to 87.40% in the first half of 2022.

GIS Analyst Jun 2020 - Jun 2021

Badan Pusat Statistik - Banjarmasin, Kalimantan Selatan

Indonesia's central statistical agency that collects, analyzes, and disseminates data to support decision-making in various sectors

- BPS manages statistical data using GIS tools, including geospatial data collection, analysis, and visualization, as well as maintaining geodatabases.
- Using shortcuts and coding to speed up area mapping and speed up regional data input such as longitude point, latitude point, census block code, RT code, and area code simultaneously.
- Successfully mapped 12 areas, 105 RT, and 70,000 houses with a 40% faster completion rate than the deadline.

The administrator of Sensus Penduduk 2020

Feb 2020 - Mei 2020

Badan Pusat Statistik - Banjarmasin, Kalimantan Selatan

Indonesia's central statistical agency that collects, analyzes, and disseminates data to support decision-making in various sectors

- Fully responsible for the administration of the population census, including coordination with local agencies for the socialization of the census.
- Monitor incoming and outgoing letters, assignments, goods and services procurement files, and population census publication materials. Archive documents monthly.
- My achievement is having knowledge in government office administration management like (SAKTI) and efficient



Data Analyst Oct 2017 - Jan 2018

PT. Geotama Energy - Yogyakarta, DIY

Companies engaged in oil, gas, and mining consulting

- Responsible for data pre-processing including data cleaning, data reduction, data transformation, and using classification algorithm
- After the data is clean, it can be classified according to the role that has been created, integrated into the model, and made a decision on the value of water saturation and clay content with FIS (Fuzzy Inference System).
- Increase model accuracy by 3% of the company model so that it becomes an insight for decision-making.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Bachelor of Mathematics

Sep 2015 - Agt 2019

University - City, Country

- GPA of 3.08/4.00
- Activity Hibah PKM-KC 2015 HOSWARD (HOT STEAM WARDROBE) as an Efficient Technology for Dressing Clothes in the Laundry Industry.
- Activity LKTIM Makassar State University 2016 Hibah PKM-KC 2015 HOSWARD (HOT STEAM WARDROBE) as an Efficient Technology for Dressing Clothes in the Laundry Industry.
- Activity FIGMA 2018 Finalist Applications to calculate the volume of space to make it easier for students to determine the volume geometry.
- Publication Thesis Value of Estimation The Operational Risks With Bayesian Method.
- Publication Research Loss Distribution Approach for Company Operational Risk Analysis.

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

Advisory Board Mathematics student association (HIMATIKA UNY) - Sleman, DIY	Jan 2018 - Dec 2018
Coordinator Makassar Regional of LSM XXVI Mathematics student association (HIMATIKA UNY) - Sleman, DIY	Dec 2017 - Feb 2018
Head of Welfare and Advocacy Mathematics student association (HIMATIKA UNY) - Sleman, DIY	Jan 2017 - Dec 2017
Deputy Seminar Event of LSM XXV Mathematics student association (HIMATIKA UNY) - Sleman, DIY	Dec 2016 - Feb 2017
The staff of Welfare and Advocacy Mathematics student association (HIMATIKA UNY) - Sleman, DIY	Jan 2016 - Dec 2016
Question Maker Competition Event of LSM XXV Mathematics student association (HIMATIKA UNY) - Sleman, DIY	Dec 2015 - Feb 2016

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION



Certification

- Data Science Python Track Dicoding (2019)
- Python Advanced Track Sanbercode(2019)
- Laravel Web Development Sanbercode(2019)
- Agile Development Sanbercode(2019)
- Front-End Web Developer Expert Track Dicoding (2020)
- Cloud Computing AWS Track Dicoding (2020)
- Data Science & ML with Python Babastudio (2020)
- Data Analyst SQL, Python Track DQLAB (2020)
- QGIS ArcGis Track Geosoftware Community
- CCNA Cyber Operation CISCO Network Academy (2021)
- Google Data Analytics Coursera(2022)
- Data Fellowship Batch 8 Data Engineer IYKRA (2023)
- Remote Work Simulation Campaign.com (2023)
- Machine Learning Terapan Dicoding (2023)
- Machine Learning Operations Dicoding (2023)
- SAP Cloud Analytics SAP Indonesia (2023)

Project

• Github: https://mzfuadi97.github.io/

